Guide to the Mordechai Littman Photograph Collection 1928-1948 PR 379
New-York Historical Society
Mordechai Littman collection of photographs
1928-1948
New-York Historical Society
Littman, Mordechai
PR 379
.5 Linear feet in one box
This collection contains photographs of classic Hollywood publicity and glamour portraiture from a variety of studios (Warner Bros, Fox, Universal, Paramount, RKO) and photographers (Roman Freulich, Hurrell, Eugene Robert Richee, Ernest Bachrach, and more), dating from 1928-1948.
Scope and Contents
This collection, assembled and donated by Mordechai Littman, contains images of classic Hollywood publicity and glamour portraiture dating from 1928-1948. The photographs originate from a variety of studios (Warner Bros, Fox, Universal, Paramount, RKO) and photographers (Roman Freulich, Hurrell, Eugene Robert Richee, Ernest Bachrach, and more). Stars depicted include Bette Davis, Joan Crawford, Richard Barthlemess, Myrna Loy, Ruby Keeler, Ralph Bellamy, Joan Blondell, Lew Ayres, Hedda Hopper, Rosalind Russell and Ray Milland.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: I) Individual Portraits (alphabetical by sitter) and II) Group Portraits and Production Stills.
Materials are varyingly stamped with photographer, date, publication, and subject information.
Conditions Governing Access
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mordechai Littman, 2013.
Separated Materials
This material was originally included in the finding aid for the Michael Sonnenfeldt Collection of Theatre, Film, and Entertainment Photography PR 305, which was processed by project intern Brynn White in 2014. This material was separated into a discrete collection and finding aid in 2019 by processing archivist Marybeth Kavanagh.
Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States -- Portraits.
- Series I. Individual Portraits and Publicity, 1930-1948; 61874
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains images of classic Hollywood publicity and glamour portraiture dating from 1930-1948, and arranged alphabetically by sitter. The photographs originate from a variety of studios (Warner Bros, Fox, Universal, Paramount, RKO) and photographers (Roman Freulich, Hurrell, Eugene Robert Richee, Ernest Bachrach, and more). Stars depicted include Bette Davis, Joan Crawford, Richard Barthlemess, Myrna Loy, Ruby Keeler, Ralph Bellamy, Joan Blondell, Lew Ayres, Hedda Hopper, Rosalind Russell and Ray Milland.
  - A-B, 1931-1939; 61875 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Allwyn, Astrid
    Angelus, Muriel
    Ayres, Lew
    Barthelmess, Richard
    Bellamy, Ralph
    Blake, Larry
    Blondell, Joan
    Boland, Mary
    Bradley, Grace
    Brown, Joe
    Buchanan, Jack
  - C-E, 1934-1946; 61876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Compton, Joyce
    Crawford, Joan
    Davis, Bette
    Dantine, Helmut
    Donohue, Jack
    Drake, Frances
    Drew, Ellen
    Ellison, James
  - F-H, 1933-1940; 61877 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Foran, Dick
    Foster, Preston
    Froman, Jane
    Gallian, Ketti
    Granville, Bonita
    Gurie, Sigrid
    Hasso, Signe
    Haydon, Julia
    Hopper, Hedda
    Howard, John
    Hutchinson, Josephine
  - J-M, 1932-1943; 61878 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Janis, Elsie
    Keeler, Ruby
    Litel, John
    Lowe, Edmund
    Loy, Myrna
    Mack, Helen
    Margo (Margo Albert)
    Milland, Ray
    Moore, Victor
    Morris, Wayne
    Montgomery, Douglass
  - O-R, 1930-1938; 61879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Oakie, Jack
    O'Keefe, Dennis
    Parsons, Harriet
    Pidgeon, Walter
    Pitts, Zasu
    Qualen, John
    Ray, Charles
    Raymond, Gene
    Rogers, Charles
    Russell, Rosalind
  - S-W, 1932-1948; 61880 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Smart, Jack
    Stephens, Harvey
    Temple, Shirley (with John Agar)
    Tobin, Genevieve
    Travis, June
    Travis, Richard
    Warfield, Marjorie
    [unidentified actor]
- Series II. Group Portraits and Publicity, 1928-1946; 61881
  This series contains images of classic Hollywood group publicity and glamour portraiture dating from 1928-1946. The photographs originate from a variety of studios (Warner Bros, Fox, Universal, Paramount, RKO) and photographers (Roman Freulich, Hurrell, Eugene Robert Richee, Ernest Bachrach, and more).
  - Group Portraits, 1929-1939; 61882 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Allan Jones and Irene Hervey
    David Newell and Jean Arthur
    Bruce Cabot, Louise Latimer, Lewis Stone, and James Gleason
    Gertrude Michael and Herbert Marshall
    Anne Shirley and Herbert Marshall
    Ann Harding and Brian Aherne
    Lola Lane, Rosemary Lane, Gale Page
    Priscilla Lane and Eddie Albert
    Claude Rains and Priscilla Lane
  - Group Portraits, 1928-1946; 61883 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Irene Dunne and Randolph Scott
    William Holden and Frank Craven
    Bette Davis and Glenn Ford
    Douglas Fairbanks Jr., Margaret Lockwood, and Will Fyffe
    Ann Sothern and Gene Raymond
    Chester Conklin and Charles "Buddy" Rogers
    Clive Brook, Evelyn Brent and Virginia Bruce